DANIEL ARAFAT TORRES RUIZ

Fullstack Developer

Languages:

Java 11+ Javascript PL/SQL Scala

Databases:

Oracle
Postgres
SQL Server

Summary:

I am Software Engineer and Backend Developer with 11 years' experience developing software projects with big companies and dynamic teams. I have knowledge in technologies and programming languages such as Java and Javascript. I have worked in different economic sectors like Insurance and Healthcare.

I have had leadership roles in development teams, I respect all opinions and ideas of my coworkers. I am very collaborative person, I am analytic for solving difficult problems, with good communication and empathy.

Technologies & Frameworks:

Spring Boot
Spring Core
Play Framework
Liquibase
Itext, Jasper
Drools
React
Angular
VueJs
Jquery
Mongo DB

Qualifications:

Educational Background: Master in Software Engineer (2020)

Specialist in Software Engineer (2015) System Computer Engineer (2009)

Certifications:

Frontend Andvanced in React (2021) Scrum Developer (2017) Scrum Master (2015)

Languages:

Spanish – Native English – B1 Level

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer		
Jun 2021 – Feb 2022		
Company: Endava	Responsibilities:	
Project descriptions: Asset Tracking System in US	Multi-Tenant Web Application. Asset monitoring via ChokePoints devices and GPS with control of alerts to know tracking data such as location, state, expiration date, etc.	
Programming languages: Java 11, AngularJS, JQuery, Postgres, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Cloud, Redis	Technologies: Microservices, Server Side Rendering, Docker	Testing and Development tools: JUnit, Thymeleaf

Backend Developer		
2021		
Company: Endava	Responsibilities:	
Project descriptions: Payment Gateway on Internal Endava Project	Study of payments standards (ISO 20022), architectures, roles and functions of payment gateways. Understanding how works and communication between Customers, Merchants, Banks, Payment Gateway, Credit/Debit card, and others.	
Programming languages: Java	Technologies: Microservices	Testing and Development tools: JUnit

Backend Developer		
March 2021 - May 2021		
Company: Endava	Responsibilities:	
Project descriptions: Account Management on Retail Company	Building logic about account management, erase account data, change password, captchas and develop common libraries between projects.	
Programming languages: Java 8	Technologies: Spring Boot, Kibana, Jenkins	Testing and Development tools: JUnit, TestAutomation

Fullstack Developer		
2019 – 2021		
Company: Ceiba	Responsibilities:	
Project descriptions: Management and diagnosis of occupational hazards on Healthcare Company	Building web pages, modules and microservices for management, operation and recommendations of the work safety, helping companies regulate their processes and complying with government laws. High communication between different applications and report generation.	
Programming languages: Java 8, Javascript - Angular 6	Technologies: Hexagonal architecture, Microservices, Reactive Programming, Play Framework, Docker, Rabbit	Testing and Development tools: JUnit, JMeter, Protractor, Manual Testing

Backend Developer			
2015 – 2019	2015 – 2019		
Company: Ceiba	Responsibilities:		
Project descriptions: Quotation and sale of insurance for companies on Insurance Company	Develop of a calculator for the promotion insurance sales for companies, according their branches and employees' count. Coverage of different types of asset accidents and how the client can collect a claim and settlements.		
Programming languages: Java 6	Technologies: Drools, GWT, Oracle, PL/SQL, Jenkins CI/CD, WebLogic, Soap Services, Itext	Testing and Development tools: JUnit, Cucumber, Manual Testing	

Daniel Torres - MSc. Software Engineer

Fullstack Developer		
2013 – 2015		
Company: Ceiba	Responsibilities:	
Project descriptions: Manage the production of the socks supply chain on Manufacturing Company	Application support for schedule and production in sock machines and textile inventory. Distribution of machine work and reserving materials using a grant diagram in the frontend.	
Programming languages: Java 5	Technologies: EJB, ORM, DB2, JavaScript, Jquery, JSP, WebDynpro, Sap NetWeaver, Itext.	Testing and Development tools: JUnit, Manual Testing

Backend Developer		
2011 – 2013		
Company: Ceiba	Responsibilities:	
Project descriptions:	Payment of retirement pension, health, occupational risks and other benefits for workers in Colombia. View and download reports for companies to validate payments from coworkers.	
Payments Labor		
Contributions on Social		
Security Company		
Programming languages: Java 5, Javascript	Technologies: Spring Core	Testing and Development tools: Manual Testing